Preliminary Inventory to the George Davis Herron Papers, 1916-1927
Hoover Institution Archives
- BOUND VOLUMES (on shelf)
  - Volume X. Russia. Crimea
    - Dr. Seidamet to Herron, 1920 November 12 (Item XI)
    - Dr. Seidamet to Herron, 1920 November 22 (Item XII)
    - Same, 1921 January 3 (Item XIII)
  - Volume XI. Switzerland
    - Preface to following letter (Item I)
    - Herron to President Wilson, 1917 May (approximately) (Item I)
    - Herron to Minister Stovall, 1917 May 26 (Item II)
    - Herron to Herrn Hoffmann, 1917 May 26 (Item III)
    - Herron to Mr. Stovall, 1917 June 2 (Item IV)
    - Herron to Professor Rappard, 1917 June 9 (Item V)
    - Herron to Minister Stovall, 1917 June 11 (Item VI)
    - Herron to Mr. Sautter, 1917 September 22 (Item VII)
    - Herron to Mr. L. Dresel, 1918 April 20 (Item VIII)
    - Transferred to League of Nations, Document III (Item IX)
    - Mr. Stovall to Herron, 1918 May 8 (Item IX-bis)
    - Herron to State Department and British Foreign Office, 1918 July 4 (Item X)
    - Mr. Stovall to Herron, 1918 July 15 (Item XI)
    - President Wilson to Mr. Stovall, 1918 June 21 (Item XI A)
    - Herron to State Department and British Foreign Office, 1918 August 26 (Item XII)
    - Same, 1918 September 7 (Item XIII)
    - Report given to Herron by Commander Whittall for the American Government, 1918 October 14 (Item XIV)
    - Herron to Mr. Dolbeare, 1918 October 16 (Item XV)
    - Transferred to The League of Nations, Document VII, which see (Item XVI)
    - M. Meyer de Stadelhofen to Herron, undated (Item XVII)
    - Herron to M. M. de Stadelhofen, 1918 December 5 (Item XVIII)
    - Marquis Paulucci di Calboli, 1918 December 5 (Item XIX)
    - Herron to Sir William Tyrrell, 1918 December 5 (Item XX)
    - Transferred to The League of Nations, Document VIII, which see (Item XXI)
    - Herron to State Department and British Foreign Office, 1919 January 4 (Item XXII)
    - Mr. George G. Sharp to Herron, 1919 January 24 (Item XXIII)
    - Transferred to The League of Nations, from Document XIII to Document XXIV (Item XXIV to XXXV)
    - Herron to Professor Constantine Stephanove, 1920 January 15 (Item XXXVI)
  - Volume XI. Switzerland. Correspondence with legations
    - Herron to Mr. Hugh R. Wilson, 1918 January 3 (Item I)
    - Mr. Hugh R. Wilson to Herron, 1918 March 21 (Item II)
    - Mr. L. Ferrière to Herron, 1918 April (Item III)
    - Herron to Mr. Hugh R. Wilson, 1918 April 30 (Item IV)
    - Herron to Mr. Hugh R. Wilson, 1918 May 29 (Item V)
    - Mr. Bland to Herron, 1918 June 10 (Item VI)
    - Herron to Mr. Dolbeare, 1918 June 16 (Item VII)
    - Mr. Bland to Herron, 1918 June 21 (Item VIII)
    - Mr. Bland to Herron, 1918 June (Item IX)
    - Mr. Bland to Herron, 1918 July 6 (Item X)
    - Mr. Bland to Herron, 1918 July 12 (Item XI)
    - Sir W. Tyrrell to Mr. Bland. Appreciation of Herron's work. Enclosure to Document XI, 1918 July 10 (Item XI A)
    - Mr. Bland to Herron, 1918 July 17 (Item XII)
    - Mr. Bland to Herron, 1918 July 25 (Item XIII)
    - Mr. Marshall to Mr. Bland, 1918 July 23 (Item XIII A)
    - Herron to Mr. Bland, 1918 July 26 (Item XIV)
    - Mr. Bland to Herron, 1918 August 15 (Item XV)
    - Sir William Tyrrell to Mr. Bland, 1918 August 14 (Item XV A)
    - Mr. Bland to Herron, 1918 August 28 (Item XVI)
    - Mr. Bland to Herron, 1918 September 2 (Item XVII)
    - Mr. Bland to Herron, 1918 September 10 (Item XVIII)
    - Mr. Bland to Herron, 1918 September 13 (Item XIX)
    - Mr. Bland to Herron, 1918 September 19 (Item XX)
    - Mr. Bland to Herron, 1918 October 2 (Item XXI)
    - Commander Whittall to Herron. Transmitting cable confirming receipt of various reports, 1918 October 10 (Item XXII)
    - Mr. Bland to Herron, 1918 October 15 (Item XXIII)
    - Mr. Bland to Herron, 1918 October 30 (Item XXIV)
    - Mr. Dulles to Herron, 1918 November 18 (Item XXV)
    - Herron to Colonel Godson, 1918 November 27 (Item XXVI)
    - Herron to Mr. Hugh R. Wilson, 1918 December 2 (Item XXVII)
    - Sir William Tyrrell to Herron, 1918 December 9 (Item XXVIII)
    - Mr. Dulles to Herron, 1919 January 3 (Item XXIX)
    - Mr. Dulles to Herron. Appointment with Secretary Lansing, 1919 January (Item XXX)
    - Mr. Hugh R. Wilson to Herron. His return to work; in charge during absence of the Minister; note from Mr. Lansing acknowledging report concerning (Item XXXI)
    - Sir William Tyrrell to Herron. Making appointment, 1919 January 20 (Item XXXII)
    - Ditto. Expressing alarm lest Herron should leave Paris without seeing him making a further appointment, 1919 January 22 (Item XXXIII)
    - Mr. Headlam Morley to Herron. Expressing pleasure at appointment for dinner, 1919 January 23 (Item XXXIV)
    - Mr. Gilbert F. Close to Herron. Replying to Herron's note of the 20th; making an appointment on behalf of The President, 1919 January 23 (Item XXXV)
    - Mr. Gilbert F. Close to Herron, 1919 January 24 (Item XXXVI)
    - Miss A.C. Keth to Herron. Making appointment with The Secretary of State, 1919 January 25 (Item XXXVII)
    - Mr. Hugh R. Wilson to Herron, 1919 February 13 (Item XXXVIII)
    - Herron to Mr. Hugh R. Wilson, 1919 February 17 (Item XXXIX)
    - Mr. McNeir to Herron. Enclosing voucher of services rendered, with request to return same, duly signed, 1919 March 15 (Item XL)
    - Mr. Hugh R. Wilson to Herron. Acknowledging letter of 28th and enclosing money order; Moran will see to the matter of Herron's request, 1919 March 29 (Item XL-bis)
    - Mr. Russell to Herron. Envelope containing confidential papers to be transmitted by Captain Jamp and left at the British Consulate for Herron to fetch, 1919 May 21 (Item XLI)
    - Mr. Gilbert F. Close to Herron. Acknowledging receipt of "Nicolle Vandel" on behalf of The President, with request that Herron convey his cordial appreciation to Mr. Tissot, 1919 May 23 (Item XLII)
    - Herron to Mr. Dulles, 1919 July 1 (Item XLIII)
    - Herron to Sir William Tyrrell, 1919 July 5 (Item XLIV)
  - Volume XI. Switzerland. Correspondence from legations
    - The Hon. Pleasant H. Stovall to Herron, 1917 May 29 (Item I)
    - Same, 1917 May 29 (Item II)
    - Same, 1917 May 30 (Item III)
    - Commander Sir Hugh E.C. Whittall to Herron, 1917 June 5 (Item IV)
    - Mr. Stovall to Herron, 1917 June 8 (Item V)
    - Same, 1917 June 9 (Item VI)
    - Same, 1917 June 30 (Item VII)
    - Commander Whittall to Herron, 1917 July 20 (Item VIII)
    - Mr. Stovall to Herron, 1917 July 26 (Item IX)
    - Same, 1917 August 2 (Item X)
    - Commander Whittall to Herron, 1917 September 17 (Item XI)
    - The Hon. William G. Sharp to Herron, 1917 December 6 (Item XII)
    - Same, 1917 December 11 (Item XIII)
    - Mr. Hugh R. Wilson to Herron, 1917 December 18 (Item XIV)
    - The Hon. Tho. Nelson Page to Herron, 1917 December 26 (Item XV)
    - Mr. Hugh R. Wilson to Herron, 1917 December 31 (Item XVI)
    - Same, 1918 January 4 (Item XVII)
    - Same, 1918 January 15 (Item XVIII)
    - Same, 1918 January 19 (Item XIX)
    - Mr. Theodore K. Shipkoff to Mr. Wilson, 1918 January 16 (Item XIX A)
    - Mr. Hugh R. Wilson to Herron, 1918 January 21 (Item XX)
    - Herron to Mr. Hugh R. Wilson, 1918 January 23 (Item XX A)
    - Mr. Hugh R. Wilson to Herron, 1918 February 18 (Item XXI)
    - Mr. Hugh R. Wilson to The Hon. William G. Sharp, 1918 February 18 (Item XXI A)
    - Mr. Stovall to Herron, 1918 March 18 (Item XXII)
    - Same, 1918 April 6 (Item XXIII)
    - Mr. Allen W. Dulles to Herron, 1918 April 9 (Item XXIV)
    - Mr. Hugh R. Wilson to Herron, 1918 May 7 (Item XXV)
    - Same, 1918 May 25 (Item XXVI)
    - Same, 1918 May 27 (Item XXVII)
    - Same, 1918 June 3 (Item XXVIII)
    - Mr. Frederic R. Dolbeare, 1918 June 17 (Item XXIX)
    - Mr. J.O.P. Bland to Herron, 1918 August 9 (Item XXX)
    - Mr. Ellis Loring Dresel to Herron, 1918 August 21 (Item XXXI)
    - Mr. Allen W. Dulles to Herron, 1918 August 23 (Item XXXII)
    - Mr. Remsen Whitehouse to Herron, 1918 September 11 (Item XXXIII)
    - Mr. Allen W. Dulles to Herron, 1918 September 20 (Item XXXIV)
    - Mr. Hugh R. Wilson to Herron, 1918 September 30 (Item XXXV)
    - Same, 1918 September 30 (Item XXXVI)
    - Mr. Remsen Whitehouse to Herron, 1918 October 2 (Item XXXVII)
    - Mr. Hubert White to Herron, 1918 October 4 (Item XXXVIII)
    - Mr. Remsen Whitehouse to Herron, 1918 October 15 (Item XXXIX)
    - Mr. Frederic R. Dolbeare to Herron, 1918 October 30 (Item XL)
    - Mr. Hugh R. Wilson to Herron, 1918 October 30 (Item XLI)
    - Mr. Allen W. Dulles to Herron, 1918 November 2 (Item XLII)
  - Volume XI. Switzerland. International societies
    - Herron to Mr. Grimm, 1916 September 20 (Item I)
    - German translation of above (Item I A)
    - Herron to Mr. Simons, 1916 September 17 (Item II)
    - Herron to Mr. Simons, 1916 September 18 (Item III)
    - Herron to Mr. Grimm, 1916 September 30 (Item IV)
    - Herron to Mr. Grimm, same date (Item V)
    - Herron to Mr. Peluso, 1916 October 3 (Item VI)
    - German translation of above (Item VI A)
    - Herron to The Editor of "Le Genevois," 1916 October 4 (Item VII)
    - Herron to Mr. Walling, 1917 May 2 (Item VIII)
    - Herron to Mr. Walling, 1917 December 27 (Item IX)
    - Commander Whittall to Herron, 1918 September 4 (Item X)
    - Herron to Mr. Krause, 1918 September 4 (Item XI)
    - Herron to Mr. Simons, 1918 September 9 (Item XII)
    - Mr. F. Bohn to Herron, 1918 December 4 (Item XIII)
    - Mr. Bohn to Herron. Telegram: Mission in Paris, 1918 December 11 (Item XIV)
    - Herron to Mr. Bohn, 1919 January 13 (Item XV)
    - Mr. F. Bohn to Herron. Telegram: Allied Socialist Conference in Paris; requesting Herron to join him, 1919 January 18 (Item XVI)
    - Herron to Mr. Strobel, 1919 October 15 (Item XVII)
  - Volume XII. Between President Wilson and Herron
    - Mr. Mitchell Kennerley to Herron, 1917 October 3 (Item I)
    - President Wilson to Mr. Kennerley, 1917 October 1 (Item I A)
    - Mr. J.C. Grew to Mr. Hugh R. Wilson, 1918 February 19 (Item II)
    - Herron to President Wilson, 1918 May 31 (Item III)
    - Mr. Hugh R. Wilson to Herron, 1918 July 6 (Item IV)
    - Mr. Hugh R. Wilson to Herron, 1918 July 6 (Item IV A)
    - Herron to The President, 1918 July 5 (Item IV B)
    - Colonel L.M. House to Herron, 1919 March 20 (Item V)
    - Herron to Mr. Gignoux, 1919 March 20 (Item VI)
    - Herron to Mr. Gignoux, 1919 March 20 (Item VI A)
    - Herron to The Hon. Pleasant H. Stovall, 1919 March 20 (Item VII)
    - Herron to President Wilson, 1919 March 20 (Item VII A)
    - Monsieur Gignoux to Herron, 1919 March 19 (Item VII B)
    - Mr. Stovall to Herron, 1919 March 21 (Item VIII)
    - Herron to Monsieur Edouard Chapuisat, 1919 March 21 (Item IX)
    - President Wilson to Herron, 1919 March 26 (Item X)
    - Monsieur Gignoux to Herron, 1919 April 12 (Item XI)
    - Herron to President Wilson, 1919 April 14 (Item XII)
    - Monsieur Gignoux to Herron, 1919 April 14 (Item XII A)
    - Same, 1919 April 14 (Item XII B)
    - The President to Herron, 1919 April 17 (Item XIII)
    - Herron to President Wilson, 1919 April 21 (Item XIV)
    - President Wilson to Herron, 1919 April 28 (Item XV)
    - Monsieur Gignoux to Herron, 1919 May 3 (Item XVI)
    - Herron to President Wilson, 1919 June (Item XVII)
    - Herron to President Wilson, 1919 September 26 (Item XVIII)
    - Herron to Colonel House, 1919 September 28 (Item XIX)
    - Colonel House to Herron, 1919 September 30 (Item XX)
    - Mr. J.P. Tumulty to Herron, 1919 October 11 (Item XXI)
    - Herron to President Wilson, 1919 October 21 (Item XXII)
    - Mr. Tumulty to Herron, 1919 October 22 (Item XXIII)
    - Herron to Colonel House, 1919 December 6 (Item XXIV)
    - Herron to Mr. Tumulty, 1919 December 6 (Item XXV)
    - Mr. Tumulty to Herron, 1919 December 27 (Item XXVI)
    - Herron to Mr. William Allen White, 1920 April 17 (Item XXVII)
    - Article in "The Berlin Herald" - The Herron-Scheffauer Controversy, 1922 April 15 (Item XXVIII)
    - Herron to Mr. William Allen White, 1924 April 30 (Item XXIX)
  - Volume XII. The League of Nations
    - Page of References to The League (Item I)
    - Herron to Mr. Hugh R. Wilson, 1918 April 14 (Item II)
    - Herron to The Hon. Pleasant H. Stovall, 1918 May 21 (Item III)
    - Herron to Mr. Wilson, 1918 May 31 (Item IV)
    - Herron to President Wilson, 1918 May 31 (Item IV A)
    - Mr. Hugh R. Wilson to Herron, 1918 July 6 (Item V)
    - Same, 1918 July 6 (Item V A)
    - Herron to President Wilson, 1918 July 5 (Item V B)
    - Herron to Mr. Hugh R. Wilson, 1918 July 8 (Item VI)
    - Mr. William Droin to Herron, 1918 December 3 (Item VII)
    - Herron to His Excellency the Hon. William G. Sharp, 1918 December 5 (Item VIII)
    - Report by Herron: American Propaganda against the President, 1919 February 5 (Item IX)
    - Mr. W.G. Middleton-Edwards to Herron, 1919 February 22 (Item X)
    - Same, 1919 March 1 (Item XI)
    - Enclosure: Constantinople - A European District of Columbia (Item XI A)
    - Mr. Middleton-Edwards to Herron, 1919 March 11 (Item XII)
    - Transferred to President Wilson's Volume (Item XIII to XIX B)
    - Mr. Middleton-Edwards to Herron, 1919 March 20 (Item XIV C)
    - Herron to The Hon. Pleasant H. Stovall, 1919 April 16 (Item XX)
    - Mr. Stovall to Herron, 1919 April 22 (Item XXI)
    - Herron to Colonel House, 1919 May 5 (Item XXII)
    - Mr. Eric Drummond to Herron, 1919 May 9 (Item XXIII)
    - Herron to President Wilson, 1919 June (Item XXIV)
    - Interview given by Herron to "Neue Zurcher Zeitung," 1919 June (Item XXV)
    - Article in "La Tribune de Genève," 1919 June 1 (Item XXVI)
    - Herron to The President, 1919 June 7 (Item XXVII)
    - Mr. Charles R. Crane to Herron, 1920 September 18 (Item XXVIII)
    - Mr. Hawkling L. Yen to Herron, 1920 November 1 (Item XXIX)
    - Herron to Mr. Crane, 1920 November 2 (Item XXX)
    - Copy of "The Social Preparation" including Herron's poem: "To America: A Psalm of Invocation," 1924 February 26 (Item XXXI)
  - Volume XIII. The Peace
    - Article by Herron: "What Terms of Peace Shall Close the..." 1914 Autumn (Item I)
    - Herron to Dr. Hillis, 1918 September 9 (Item II)
    - Mr. J.O.P. Bland to Herron, 1918 November 27 (Item III)
    - Herron to Mr. Bland, 1918 December 4 (Item IV)
    - Herron to Mr. Hugh R. Wilson, 1919 January 13 (Item V)
    - Report made by Herron at request of the Secretary of State, Mr. Robert Lansing, 1919 January 22 (Item VI)
    - Herron to The Rt. Hon. Sir William Tyrrell, 1919 February 4 (Item VII)
    - Professor L. Ragaz to Herron, 1919 March 29 (Item VIII)
    - Herron to Professor Ragaz, 1919 April 1 (Item IX)
    - Herron to Sir William Tyrrell, 1919 April 8 (Item IX A)
    - Mr. E.J. Dillon to Herron, 1919 April 10 (Item X)
    - Herron to Mr. Dillon, 1919 April 15 (Item XI)
    - Herron to The Hon. Pleasant H. Stovall, 1919 April 24 (Item XII)
    - Herron to Mr. Frank W. Vanderlip, 1919 May 27 (Item XIII)
    - Herron to Sir William Tyrrell, 1919 July 3 (Item XIV)
    - Herron to Mr. C.A. Barron, 1919 September 15 (Item XV)
    - Herron to Mr. Ralph de Cazenove, 1919 October 4 (Item XVI)
    - Mr. Charles R. Crane to Herron, 1919 October 12 (Item XVII)
    - Herron to Mr. Crane, 1919 October 13 (Item XVIII)
    - Herron to Mr. Crane, 1919 October 14 (Item XIX)
    - Note by Mr. Anderson, 1919 October 15 or 16 (Item XX)
    - Report on Economic Tasks by Mr. Leo Wulfsohn, 1919 October 9 (Item XX A)
    - Herron to Colonel House, 1919 October 18 (Item XXI)
    - Appendix by Mr. Leo Wulfsohn, 1919 October 16 (Item XXI A)
    - Herron to Mr. J.P. Tumulty, 1919 December 11 (Item XXII)
    - Mr. Tumulty to Herron, 1920 January 8 (Item XXIII)
  - Volume XIII. The Peace - Dillon Annex
    - Mr. E.J. Dillon to Herron, 1919 April 10 (Item I)
    - Herron to Mr. Dillon, 1919 April 15 (Item II)
    - Mr. Dillon to Herron, 1919 April 23 (Item III)
    - Herron to Mr. Dillon, 1919 April 30 (Item IV)
    - Mr. E.J. Dillon to Herron, 1919 May 3 (Item V)
    - Same, 1919 May 5 (Item VI)
    - Herron to Mr. Dillon, 1919 May 6 (Item VII)
    - Mr. Dillon to Herron, 1919 May 9 (Item VIII)
    - Herron to Mr. Dillon, 1919 May 13 (Item IX)
    - Mr. Dillon to Herron, 1919 May 23 (Item X)
    - Herron to Mr. Dillon, 1919 May 28 (Item XI)
  - Volume XIII. The Peace - Barron Annex
    - Mr. C.W. Barron to Herron, 1918 December 21 (Item I)
    - Herron to Mr. Barron, 1919 January 18 (Item II)
    - Mr. Barron to Herron, 1919 February 10 (Item III)
    - Same, 1919 April 29 (Item IV)
    - Herron to Mr. Barron, 1919 May 16 (Item V)
    - Mr. Barron to Herron, 1919 June 12 (Item VI)
    - Mr. Barron to Herron, 1919 August 23 (Item VII)
    - Herron to Mr. Barron, 1919 September 15 (Item VIII)
    - Memorandum made by Mr. Frederick U. Bates (Item VIII A)
    - Herron to Mr. Barron, 1919 October 18 (Item IX)
    - Mr. Barron to Herron, 1919 November 12 (Item X)
    - Mr. D.C. Harrower to Mr. Barron, 1919 October 21 (Item X A)
    - Herron to Mr. Barron, 1919 December 6 (Item XI)
    - Herron to Mr. Barron, 1919 December 10 (Item XII)
    - Herron to Mr. Barron, 1920 February 24 (Item XIII)
    - Herron to Mr. Barron, 1920 February 27 (Item XIV)
    - Herron to Mr. Barron, 1920 March 8 (Item XX)
  - Volume XIII. Dr. Paul Sabatier
    - Dr. Paul Sabatier to Herron, 1916 October 5 (Item I)
    - Same, 1916 October 25 (Item II)
    - Same, 1917 February 3 (Item III)
    - Same, 1917 September 12 (Item IV)
    - Herron to Dr. Sabatier, 1917 September 22 (Item V)
    - Dr. Sabatier to Herron, 1918 October 13 (Item VI)
    - Dr. Sabatier to Herron, 1918 December 5 (Item VII)
    - English translation of above (Item VII A)
    - Dr. Sabatier to Herron, 1918 December 20 (Item VIII)
    - M.L. Ferrière to Herron, 1918 December 30 (Item VIII A)
    - English translation of Document VIII (Item VIII B)
    - Herron to Dr. Sabatier, 1918 December 22 (Item IX)
    - Dr. Sabatier to Herron, 1918 December 27 (Item X)
    - Herron to Dr. Sabatier, 1918 December 28 (Item XI)
    - Report to State Department and British Foreign Office, 1918 December 31 (Item XII)
  - Volume XIII. Colonel MacHugh
    - Colonel MacHugh to Herron, 1918 November 1 (Item I)
    - Colonel R.J. MacHugh to Herron, 1918 November 13 (Item II)
    - Colonel MacHugh to Herron, 1918 November 15 (Item III)
    - Colonel MacHugh to Herron, 1918 November 22 (Item IV)
    - Colonel MacHugh to Herron, 1918 November 26 (Item V)
    - Colonel MacHugh to Herron, 1918 November 27 (Item VI)
    - Colonel MacHugh to Herron, 1918 November 29 (Item VII)
    - Colonel MacHugh to Herron, 1918 November 30 (Item VIII)
    - Colonel MacHugh to Herron, 1918 December 4 (Item IX)
    - Colonel MacHugh to Herron, 1919 January 13 (Item X)
    - Colonel MacHugh to Herron, 1919 January 18 (Item XI)
  - Volume XIII. Eugene V. Debs
    - Eugene V. Debs to Herron, 1916 June 3 (Item I)
    - Same, 1916 November 16 (Item II)
    - Herron to Eugene V. Debs, 1916 December 19 (Item III)
    - Eugene V. Debs to Herron, 1917 January 23 (Item IV)
    - Same, 1918 January 26 (Item V)
    - Herron to President Wilson, 1919 September 26 (Item VI)
    - Herron to Eugene V. Debs, 1919 September 26 (Item VII)
    - Colonel House to Herron, 1919 September 30 (Item VIII)
    - Mr. Tumulty to Herron, 1919 October 11 (Item IX)
    - Theodore Debs to Herron, 1919 October 22 (Item X)
    - Same, 1919 October 31 (Item XI)
    - Herron to Colonel House, 1919 December 6 (Item XII)
    - Herron to Mr. Tumulty, 1919 December 6 (Item XIII)
    - Mr. Tumulty to Herron, 1919 December 27 (Item XIV)
  - Volume XIV. Supplementary: Germany - Austria
    - Count Stefan Tisza - Report. Political situation in Austria and Hungary; recommending understanding between Austro-Hungary and Germany, with a view better relations of Central Powers with Bulgaria, Roumania, Greece and Turkey, 1914 March 15 (Item I)
    - Count Tisza to Emperor Franz Joseph of Austria. Request for immediate mobilization in order to avert unsatisfactory answer and attitude of Serbia, 1914 July 25 (Item II)
    - Unsigned Secret Document. Various war solutions in Austro-Hungary, in the event of victory or otherwise, 1914 December (Item III)
    - Kaiser Wilhelm to Emperor Franz-Joseph. Italy's attitude, 1915 January 9 (Item IV)
    - Emperor Franz-Joseph to Kaiser Wilhelm. Conveyed by nephew Charles; Italy's attitude, 1915 January 20 (Item V)
    - Cardinal Gasparri to Apostolic Nuncio in Austro-Hungary. Giving explanation of nomination in favor of French Cardinals in lieu of German ones; solemnities for the death of Emperor Franz-Joseph; answering complaints regarding better consideration of Italian prisoners instead of Austrian ones; giving reasons, 1917 February 20 (Item VI)
    - Ambassador Schönburg to Count Czernin. Secret; interview with Mr. Erzberger regarding peace negotiations, 1917 May 24 (Item VII)
    - Secret Document in State Archives - Vienna. Signed P.A.; war aims and understanding between Germany and Austria for the future, 1917 October 22 (Item VIII)
  - Index to Supplementary Volume.
    - Prefatory
      - Foreword: CONFERENCES OR NEGOTIATIONS CONCERNING WHICH THE DOCUMENTS ARE LOST OR REPORTS OF WHICH WERE ONLY VERBAL (Item I)
      - Herron to The Hon. Joseph C. Grew, 1923 June 22 (Item II)
      - Mr. Grew to Herron, 1923 June 29 (Item III)
      - Herron to Mr. Hugh R. Wilson, 1923 July 21 (Item IV)
    - Supplementary: Germany
      - Article by Herron on Admiral von Hintze, 1918 August 3 (Item I)
      - Article by Herron on Dr. Muehlon, 1918 August 10 (Item II)
      - Appeal given to Herron by Professor Foerster, 1920 Autumn (Item III)
      - Herron to Count Montgelas, 1923 January 21 (Item IV)
      - Herron to Count Montgelas, 1923 March 6 (Item V)
      - Herron to Count Montgelas, 1923 March 20 (Item VI)
    - Supplementary: Austria
      - Article by Herron on Austria and Italy, 1917 March 22 (Item I)
      - Article by Herron: "The World at the Cross-Roads," early 1918 (Item II)
      - Article by Herron: "America's Answer to Austria," end of 1918 (Item III)
      - Article by Herron: "A Golden Bridge Unbuilt," 1921 December (Item IV)
    - Supplementary: Italy
      - Herron to Mr. William Allan White, 1920 April 17 (Item I)
      - Herron to The Rev. Norman Thomas, 1920 May 7 (Item II)
      - Herron to Onorevole Signor Benito Mussolini, 1922 August 26 (Item III)
      - Mussolini to Herron, 1922 August 29 (Item IV)
      - Herron to Marquis Paulucci di Calboli, 1922 December 13 (Item V)
      - Herron to Duca Colonna di Cesarò, 1923 January 20 (Item VI)
      - Herron to Duca Colonna di Cesarò, 1923 January 21 (Item VII)
      - Herron to Duca Colonna di Cesarò, 1923 January 29 (Item VIII)
      - Herron to Duca Colonna di Cesarò, 1923 March 2 (Item IX)
      - Herron to Miss Vida D. Scudder, 1923 March 5 (Item X)
      - Herron to Marquis R. Paulucci di Calboli, 1923 March 15 (Item XI)
    - Supplementary: Italy and Serbia
      - M. Savtchitch to Herron, 1917 September 12 (Item I)
      - Dr. L. Marcovitch to Herron, 1918 June 11 (Item II)
      - Same, 1918 August 15 (Item III)
      - Same, 1918 August 27 (Item IV)
      - Same, 1918 September 23 (Item V)
      - Same, 1918 October 7 (Item VI)
      - Article in "IDEA NAZIONALE" (Herron & Kramer), 1919 April 14 (Item VII)
      - Article in "THE GLOBE" - A Financial Coalition, 1919 May 16 (Item VIII)
    - Supplementary: Russia
      - Herron to The Rt. Rev. Bishop Paul Jones, 1920 January 27 (Item I)
    - Supplementary: The Near East - Armenia
      - Herron to Mrs. Charles Berry, 1923 November 10 (Item I)
    - Supplementary: France
      - Editor of "THE WORLD" to Herron, 1921 October 28 (Item I)
      - Mr. J.O.H. Cosgrave to Herron, 1922 January 19 (Item I A)
      - Article by Herron - "The Truth about France," undated (Item I B)
    - Supplementary: Germany